# Kelly Williams

+64 272 466 642 - kellymarjoriewilliams@gmail.com

**Q** <u>kellymarjorie.github.io</u>

github.com/kellymarjorie

in <u>kellywilliams</u>

#### **About**

I am an energetic and enthusiastic designer, and I use my Bachelor of Fine Arts while also pulling from my unique experience working internationally to create beautiful digital experiences, and with a working history in IT, I have the research and management skills to see projects through from beginning to end. I have recently returned from three years living and working Japan, where I have spent the past six months studying and bringing my design and development skills up to standard, and am now seeking a challenging and rewarding position to begin my career in Web Design.

## **Skills**

HTML5, CSS3 (Sass, Bootstrap), JavaScript (jQuery), RESTful API, Sketch App, Adobe CS (Ps/Ai/Id), prototyping (Principle), VS Code, Git and Github, command line/terminal, Trello, Jira

## **Interests**

Photography, drawing, painting, illustration, reading, typography, traveling, languages, history

## **Strengths**

- Excellent written and verbal communication; comfortable with presenting, interviewing and documenting technical procedures.
- Strong problem solving skills, with a persistent and creative approach to finding solutions for new and unusual issues.
- Quick at understanding and mastering new technologies and programs, being extremely motivated to continually improve my knowledge and skillset.
- Extensive experience in client facing roles either in person, over the phone, or by email, and including researching technical needs and handling complaints.
- Strong familiarity with both Windows and OSX operating systems.
- Experience working in both lean and agile environments, and with DevOps practices.

## **Education**

Whitecliffe College of Arts and Design Bachelor of Fine Arts 2006 - 2009 FreeCodeCamp (online bootcamp)
Front-end Web Development
April 2017 - present

## **Professional Experience**

09/2014 - **Abroad International School** - Nagoya, Japan 03/2017 *Preschool ESL Teacher* 

- Increased my class size from four in my first year to 18 with a wait list in my final year, through creating a positive learning experience based on the visual impact of design elements in the classroom.
- Recognised the importance of a great relationship with parents identifying expectations,
  what they each defined as success, and maintaining consistent communication. One of the
  outcomes from this investigation was that I created an end of year review portfolio for each
  child with a heavy visual element; this was received so well it has been adopted by the
  school for all classrooms.
- Assisted the school management in their exchanges in English to parents when neither party were native speakers, by drafting and proofreading digital and printed correspondence.

- Assisted in the roll-out of CRM (Salesforce) system; I was responsible for user training and part of the team for system administration and data management, including data entry.
- Managed in-house training workshops; I interviewed employees to find out their training requirements and then planned and delivered workshops to cater to those needs.
- Worked with Project Managers and Business Analysts to provide technical support and working systems to meet their needs but still within the strict government guidelines.
- Provided administration based assistance to the EDRMS project team, which included monitoring use of the system, assigning user permissions, and delivering new employee training.
- Supported the development of internal user guides to uplift in-house self-service capabilities.

- Part of the team that delivered national company workshops to unit and understand the different demands and processes of each division. This involved arranging outside professionals to provide onsite education presentations or holding Q&A seminars, as well as creating an employee platform (Sharepoint) for best practices to be shared.
- Supervised a second tier support Mobile IT helpdesk, and consistently met and raised SLA

- targets, surpassing previous benchmarks.
- Took ownership of the project to create and maintain process documentation, versed with the Lean method, to ensure a consistent approach for communication and issue resolution for the helpdesk team, end users, and for an external first-tier helpdesk.
- Instrumental in raising a position image of IT within the company with excellent customer service, measured by internal surveys. Nominated three times for a company customer service awards program, winning once.
- Primary liaison with company mobile service provider and multiple external mobile IT companies.
- Sole management of the company's mobile connection contract, averaging at £150,000 a
  month. This included asset management, monitoring costs on 8500+ connections, decision
  making on new contracts and procurement options, and analysing billing data and reporting
  back on this to different levels of management.
- Oversaw the end to end process of implementing an online mobile device billing software for over 8000 end users.
- Assisted in the mobile device appropriation for new and existing government and public service contracts.

08/2011 - 12/2011	Amey PLC - Oxford, United Kingdom  Mobiles Administrator
04/2011 - 07/2011	<b>Prego Cafe and Cocktail Bar</b> - Darlington, United Kingdom Bartender
08/2010 -	<b>Spark (Telecom)</b> - Christchurch, New Zealand
02/2011	<i>Communications Consultant</i>
02/2010 -	<b>Madras Cafe Bookshop</b> - Christchurch New Zealand
08/2010	<i>Cafe Manager</i>
12/2008 -	<b>NOOD</b> - Christchurch, New Zealand
02/2010	Cafe barista, Retail Assistant

## References

Available on request.